STEPHEN GARRETT DEWYER

full-stack web developer | user experience designer

portfolio: www.stephendewyerwebwork.com

3136 Hennepin Avenue, #4 Minneapolis, Minnesota 55408 stephen.dewyer@stephengdewyer.info 248-766-8556

career objective

An award-winning full-stack web developer and UX designer with over ten years of experience creating groundbreaking web programs for organizations. Experienced in working with multiple stakeholders to produce critically-acclaimed projects that have been featured in The New York Times, Artnet News and Detroit News. Effective at bringing together disparate parts of the community through multi-disciplinary projects. Passionate about creating software that empowers communities to solve challenging problems.

full-stack web development and UX design skills

- Programming languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python
- Stylesheet languages: CSS 3 • Markup languages: HTML 5
- JavaScript compilers, frameworks and libraries: SvelteKit, Svelte, Next.js, React, Vue.js, Express, Han-
- Server environments: Node
- Development environments: Visual Studio, Php-
- Data interchange formats: JSON
- Database management systems: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Application Programming Interfaces (APIs): Representational state transfer (REST), GraphQL
- Machine learning
- **UX design:** wire framing, prototyping, user research, user testing, information architecture, user flows, user interviews
- Digital media: Adobe Creative Cloud, photography, videography, graphic design, brand identity design, animation
- Prototype design: Figma
- Web accessibility standards: WCAG 2.1
- Version control systems: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket
- **Geocoding:** TomTom, Google Maps
- Data Visualization: D3.js
- eCommerce: Stripe

professional experience

2021 – present, Founding Director, Full-stack Web **Developer and UX Designer**

Art in Tech Services Inc

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Created dynamic, accessible and responsive web programs including client collaboration software
- Works with clients to plan and achieve digital product
- Provides UX design for enterprise web programs
- Leads strategy for making digital products using advancements in art and digital technology

2017 – present, Founder, Full-stack Web Developer and UX Designer

Public Arts Commission

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Leading the redesign of the organization's website to provide personalized connections between voters, actions and campaigns for greater democracy within and outside art
- Conducted user tests for web prototypes with Board of Directors and art experts
- Designs brand and media
- Created a web portal used by campaigns to apply for endorsement
- Works with Board of Directors to achieve organizational
- Responsible for overall direction of the non-profit, 501(c) (4) organization

2022, UX Design Consultant (contract) **Turnberry Solutions**

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Created high-fidelity prototypes to personalize dental insurance plan shopping in the Federal Employees Dental and Vision Insurance Program (FEDVIP)
- Helped empower teams to produce great UX design for enterprise web products
- Client: FedPoint

2013 – 2017, Web Developer and UX Designer / **Co-Founding Editor**

∞ *mile* (Infinite Mile LLC)

Detroit, Michigan

- Collaborated with stakeholders to create brand and
- Led a monthly online, Detroit-based art journal that published yearly print anthologies
- Directed editing staff and contributors
- Wrote successful grant applications

 Partnered with the University of Michigan Stamps School of Art & Design to produce two serial publications and conferences

teaching experience

2015 – 2017, Lecturer University of Detroit Mercy School of Architecture Digital Media Department

Detroit, Michigan

2015 – 2016, Special Lecturer 2014 – 2015, Lecturer Oakland University Department of Art & Art History Rochester, Michigan

websites created

- 2021 present, Art in Tech Services Inc www.artintechservices.com
- 2023, Suzanne Conti Quilts
 https://suzannecontiquilts.vercel.app
- 2022, JoyFoodly www.joyfoodly.com
- 2021 present, web work portfolio www.stephendewyerwebwork.com
- 2017 present, Public Arts Commission https://public-arts-commission.vercel.app
- 2013 2017, ∞ mile (Infinite Mile) www.infinitemiledetroit.com
- 2008 present, artist website www.stephengdewyer.info

technical training

2021 – 2023, Certificates in UX Design, Web Development and Web Accessibility, Udemy

- Understanding TypeScript
- Machine Learning A-Z™: Al, Python & R + ChatGPT Bonus [2023]
- GraphQL by Example
- Svelte.js The Complete Guide (incl. Sapper.js)
- NodeJS The Complete Guide (MVC, REST APIs, Graph-QL, Deno)
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux)
- Web Accessibility Training Course WCAG 2.1 Compliance
- The User Researcher's guide to UX discoveries

tions, University of Michigan - Coursera

- · JavaScript, jQuery, and JSON
- Interactivity with JavaScript
- Building Database Applications in PHP
- Introduction to Structured Query Language (SQL)
- Building Web Applications in PHP

2021, Certificates in Database Design, University of Michigan – Coursera

- Intermediate PostgreSQL
- Database Design and Basic SQL in PostgreSQL

2020, Certificates in Python Programming, University of Michigan – Coursera

- Python Data Structures
- Python for Everybody

2020, Certificates in UX Design, Interaction Design Foundation

- UI Design Patterns for Successful Software
- Mobile User Experience (UX) Design
- Become a UX Designer from Scratch
- Human-Computer Interaction

2021, Certificate in Leadership, University of Michigan – Coursera

• Inspiring and Motivating Individuals

awards and grants

2014 – 2016, Knight Arts Challenge Detroit matching \$20,000 grant for ∞ *mile*John S. and James L. Knight Foundation

Miami, Florida

2014, Detroit Chapter June 2014 \$1,000 grant for ∞ *mile*

Awesome Foundation

Boston, Massachusetts

education

2009 – 2011, Master of Fine Arts (MFA) in Sculpture Yale University School of Art

New Haven, Connecticut

2005 – 2008, Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA) *cum laude* in Art History, Theory & Criticism Maryland Institute College of Art (MICA)

Baltimore, Maryland